anixter.com 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy | Anixter

## What is this policy about?

This policy sets out how we conduct any activity involving the use of personal information of our employees, customers, suppliers and other third parties. That is commonly referred to as personal information “processing”.  
Personal information or personal data is any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. The medium in which such information is stored or whether it relates to past employees, suppliers or any other individuals is irrelevant.  
This policy sets out what we expect from you to ensure that we comply with personal data protection laws that apply to Anixter.  As part of our commitment to data privacy, we also comply with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union (EU) and Switzerland to the United States. See “Transfer Limitation” below and Annex A to this policy to learn more about the Privacy Shield program.

## Who this policy applies to?

This policy applies to Anixter Inc and each of its subsidiaries. For simplicity, throughout this policy, “we”, “us” and “Anixter” mean each of Anixter Inc and its subsidiaries.  
You must read, understand and comply with this policy when handling personal information and attend training on its requirements. If you or your team handles employee personal information transferred from EU or Switzerland, please also follow (and ensure your team follows) the guidance attached at **Annex A**.  
This policy is split into sections. Each section explains the requirements and contains “how to comply” boxes that explain the steps you need to take to comply with this policy.

## Key principles for protecting personal information

**Summary of the principles  
**When processing personal information, we comply with the following principles, which require that personal information is:

  * Processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner (Lawfulness, Fairness and Transparency).
  * Collected only for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes (Purpose Limitation).
  * Adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which it is processed (Data Minimization).
  * Accurate and where necessary kept up to date (Accuracy).
  * Not kept in a form which permits identification of an individual for longer than necessary for the purposes for which the information is processed (Storage Limitation).
  * Processed in a manner that ensures its security using appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction of damage (Security, Integrity and Confidentiality).
  * Not transferred to another country without appropriate safeguards in place (Transfer Limitation).
  * Made available to individuals to whom personal information relates and that those individuals can exercise their lawful rights in relation to their personal information (Data Subject's Rights and Requests).

We are responsible for and must demonstrate compliance with the above principles (Accountability).

**Lawfulness, Fairness and Transparency  
**You may only collect, process and share personal information, if you have lawful basis to do so. Typically, we will process personal information under the following bases.

  * **Consent.**  If an individual has consented for his or her personal information to be processed in a certain way, we are free to do so. That consent should be freely given, informed, specific and unambiguous. A good example is our marketing team using an individual’s email address to send an invitation to an event.
  * **Contract.**  Where we have entered into a contract with an individual, we may need to process personal information. The most common example is a contract of employment.  For example, we need bank account details to pay our employees. 
  * **Compliance with legal obligations.**  Quite simply, if we need to keep personal information to comply with applicable laws, we can. For example, we may be required to keep certain medical information about our employees to comply with occupational health and safety rules.
  * **Legitimate interests**. This is the most flexible basis for processing personal information. There is no detailed list and the easiest way to determine whether there is a legitimate interest is to consider whether personal information is processed in way people would reasonably expect. For example, our customers will expect we will use their employee personal data to process orders.

Where we use consent to process personal information, that consent must have been given by a statement or positive action. Pre-ticked boxes or inactivity are unlikely to be sufficient to obtain consent. Further, individuals must be able to withdraw their consent at any time and we must stop processing their personal data, unless we can rely on another lawful basis for processing.

We also must be transparent about how we process personal information. The legislation that applies to Anixter requires us to provide detailed and specific information about personal information processing. This is done through Employee and Business Partner Privacy Notices.

When information is collected directly from an individual, the relevant notice must be provided at the time personal information is collected. If we collect personal information indirectly (for example, form a recruitment agency), then the notice must be provided as soon as possible after collecting that personal information.

_**How to comply?  
**__Anixter has put in place mechanisms to ensure that personal information of our employees, customers and suppliers is processed lawfully, fairly and transparently. Our privacy notices are included in new hire packets and credit application forms.  _ _This means that in most instances we will have thought about the basis for processing and incorporating privacy notices in the relevant communications and documents. However, if you routinely collect personal information that becomes part of Anixter’s systems and are unsure or believe that we are not being transparent about how that information is used, please email[dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com)._

**Purpose Limitation  
**Personal information must be collected only for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes and must not be used for purposes that are incompatible with the purposes for which personal information was originally collected, unless the individual was informed of the new purposes or, if required, consented.

_**How to comply?  
**__The purposes for which Anixter uses personal information are set out in our Privacy Notices, but you need to be wary of circumstances where personal information is used outside of those purposes or is used for an unexpected purpose.   For example, if we have collected personal information of an individual to process our customer’s order, we cannot then pass their contact details to a third party for marketing purposes, unless that individual has consented or such transfer is within our legitimate interest and that individual was informed of that legitimate interest._

**Data Minimisation**  
Personal information must be adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which it is processed. For example, if you need to run a credit check on a director guaranteeing our customer’s obligations, you can only collect information that credit agency requires.

_**How to comply?  
**__\- You may only process personal information when your job requires it. You cannot process such information for any reason unrelated to your job.  
__\- You may only collect personal information that you require for your job duties. Do not collect excessive amounts of personal information.  
__\- Ensure that personal information you collect is relevant and adequate for the intended purpose of processing.  
__\- Delete or anonymize personal information in accordance with Anixter’s document retention policies._

**Accuracy  
**Personal information must be accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date.

_**How to comply?  
**__\- You must check the accuracy of any personal information when you collect it.  
\- You must take all reasonable steps to destroy or amend inaccurate or out of date personal information._

_We understand that individuals may make mistakes when providing you with their personal information.   You therefore are not required to go out of your way to validate that information, but you need to take reasonable steps, for example, by correcting typing errors.   
__If an individual requests their data be corrected, you must correct it in accordance with our processes or, if that is not possible, ask your manager for guidance. You need to ensure that the request to correct personal information comes from an individual whose information is being corrected._

**Storage limitation  
**Personal information must not be kept in a way that identifies an individual for longer that is required for the purposes for which that information is processed.

_**How to comply?  
**\- You must follow Anixter’s document retention policy applicable to your region.  
\- You must not keep personal information in a form which permits identification of individuals for longer than necessary for the relevant purpose, including the purpose of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements.  
\- You will take all reasonable steps to destroy or erase personal information from our systems, on expiry of the applicable retention period._

## Protecting personal information

**General guidance for protecting personal information  
**The law requires that personal information is secured by appropriate technical and organisational measures against unauthorized or unlawful processing, and against accidental loss, destruction or damage. We have developed and implemented and will continue to develop and implement safeguards that are appropriate to our business and personal information that we process.  Examples of such controls include:

  * Segmented access controls
  * Disaster recovery plans
  * Incident response plans
  * User limits
  * Password protection
  * Encryption of information (in transit)
  * Network Authentication
  * Access controls
  * Server access controls

_**How to comply?**  
- ** ** You must follow the applicable [policies](http://marcom.anixter.com/Ethics-and-legal/Ethics-and-Compliance-Policies.html) and procedures that we have put in place to protect personal information,   
such as:  
__o     Ethics Policy  
__o     [Security Guidelines and Policies](http://cor-prod-01.anixter.com/security/secstand.nsf/SecurityCatagory?OpenForm) (if applicable)  
__\- You must exercise particular care to protect sensitive personal information.  
__\- If you believe that there is no specific process that applies to your function, you must take reasonable steps to protect personal information. For example, password protecting spreadsheets that contain sensitive personal information or large amounts of personal information.  
__\- You must protect confidentiality of personal information in accordance with our[confidentiality policy](http://marcom.anixter.com/Ethics-and-legal/Ethics-and-Compliance-Policies.html#Confidentiality).  
__\- You must comply with and not attempt to circumvent the administrative, physical and technical safeguards we implement and maintain in accordance with the law._

**Reporting a personal information breach  
**Some jurisdictions where we operate require us to notify regulators of certain material breaches of personal information and, in some circumstances, individuals to whom personal information that has been compromised relates.  
We have put in place procedures to deal with personal information breaches. Remember that personal information breach is any act or omission that compromises the security, confidentiality, integrity or availability of personal information or safeguards that are in place to protect personal information. The loss, or unauthorised access, disclosure or acquisition is also a personal information breach.  
We remind you that Anixter does not retaliate against employees who report violations of our policies or the law. The anti-retaliation policy can be found [here](http://marcom.anixter.com/Ethics-and-legal/Ethics-and-Compliance-Policies.html#Retaliation).

_**How to comply?**  
\- If you are aware or suspect personal information breach you must follow the policy that applies to your department (for example, IS Incident Response policy) or contact [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).  Do not attempt to investigate the breach yourself, unless you have been designated as the investigator in accordance with our procedures.  
__\- You must preserve all evidence relating to the breach._

## Transfer limitation

The laws of some jurisdictions permit transfers overseas only in certain circumstances.  For example, the EU and Swiss legislation restricts transfers of personal information to countries outside the EEA (the EU, Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway) and Switzerland, respectively, that do not offer similar level of protection of personal information as EU / Swiss laws.  
As you know, Anixter is a global organisation, headquartered in the USA.  Inevitably, we will transfer some personal information to our HQ in Glenview.  
In relation to employee personal information, Anixter complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively.  Anixter has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Please see the Privacy Shield website for the list of entities covered under Anixter’s Privacy Shield self-certification. With respect to personal Information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Anixter is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission and commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC).  
With respect to personal information of our customers and suppliers, we have put in place intercompany EU Model Clauses.  This is a contract approved by the European Commission that allows individuals to enforce their EU legal rights against US organisations that have entered into such contracts.

_**How to comply?  
**_**_-  _**Although we have put measures in place to allow international transfers of personal information, if you are based in the EU or Switzerland _and_ intend to transfer large amounts of personal information or sensitive personal information overseas, please email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).  
\- If you or your team handles employee personal information transferred from EU or Switzerland, in addition to this policy, please follow and ensure your team follows the guidance attached at **Annex A**.

## Individual’s rights and requests

Individuals, whose personal information we process, have certain rights over their personal information.  These rights vary globally, but typically include the following rights to:

  * Withdraw consent to processing of their personal information
  * Receive information about how we process their personal information
  * Request access to their personal information
  * Prevent use of their personal information for direct marketing purposes
  * In certain circumstances, ask to erase, restrict processing or object to processing of personal information
  * Challenge the legal basis for processing personal information
  * In limited circumstances, be notified of personal information breach
  * Make a complaint to the relevant authority
  * Transfer their personal information to a third party
  * Request copy of agreement that is used to transfer data to outside EEA

_**How to comply?  
**\- You need to be able to identify a request to exercise individual rights in relation to personal information and must follow the guidance attached at **Annex B.  
**\- You **_must not_** attempt to deal with any of the above requests yourself, unless a specific process has been implemented by Anixter that applies to a particular request.  
\- You must email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com) if you believe that an individual wishes to exercise his or her rights relating to his or her personal information._

## Accountability

**Overview  
**We have implemented appropriate measures to ensure compliance with data privacy laws. We are also responsible for demonstrating compliance with the principles for protecting personal information.

  * We have put in place a Data Privacy Committee. This committee sits in Glenview HQ and is responsible for overseeing our legal obligations relating to protecting personal information. The committee includes senior management, our Chief Compliance Officer and representatives of various functions in our organization.
  * We are implementing privacy by design approach (see below).
  * We will be conducting Data Privacy Impact Assessment or DPIAs where necessary (see below).
  * We have integrated the principles for protecting personal information into our internal documents such as this policy, Employee Privacy Policy, Business Partner Privacy Policy and Data Privacy Committee Charter.
  * We will be rolling out and regularly conducting training on data privacy laws and this policy.
  * We are regularly testing our security measures.

_**How to comply?  
 - **When requested, you must compete training on processing personal information._

**EU record of processing activities  
**The EU legislation requires us to keep a record of our processing activities. We have conducted a detailed data discovery exercise and prepared the necessary documents.We have also assigned responsibility for maintaining the record of processing activities.

_**How to comply?  
**\- If you are about to engage a new processor of personal information that will process EU personal information, please contact [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).  Examples of such processors include payroll agencies, credit check providers and travel management companies.  
\- If you are going to collect and process personal data for a purpose that is not listed in our privacy notices, please contact [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com)._

**Privacy by design  
**Privacy by design means that we implement appropriate technical and organisational measures in an effective manner to ensure compliance with applicable data privacy laws. We believe that privacy by design measures should be implemented on all programs, systems and processes that process personal information. In the EU privacy by design is a legal requirement. When implementing privacy by design measures, we should take into account:

  * The state of the art
  * The cost of implementation
  * The nature, scope, context and purposes of processing personal information
  * The risks to and severity for rights and freedoms of individuals posed by the processing of their personal information.

In the EU, a DPIA must be conducted if we intend to:  

  * Use systematic and extensive profiling with significant effects
  * Process sensitive personal information or criminal offence data on a large scale
  * Systematically monitor publicly accessible places on a large scale

_**How to comply?  
**We understand that it may be difficult to determine when a DPIA is required.  You therefore should email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com) if you believe that a DPIA may be required. Examples of when DPIA might be needed include:  
__\- We intend to implement a technology that automatically rejects a job application of an individual, whose profile does not fit the job requirements.  
__\- We plan to track location of our employees (e.g. drivers) and make decisions based on their delivery targets._

**DPIA  
**Where a type of processing, in particular using new technologies, is likely to result in high risk to the rights and freedoms of individuals, we must conduct a Data Privacy Impact Assessment or DPIA.  
A DPIA may be required if we plan to:

  * Use new technologies that may materially affect rights and freedoms of individuals
  * Use profiling to decide on access to our services
  * Process biometric or genetic data
  * Track individuals’ location or behaviour
  * Profile individuals on a large scale

In the EU, a DPIA must be conducted if we intend to:

  * Use systematic and extensive profiling with significant effects
  * Process sensitive personal information or criminal offence data on a large scale
  * Systematically monitor publicly accessible places on a large scale

_**How to comply?  
**We understand that it may be difficult to determine when a DPIA is required.  You therefore should email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com) if you believe that a DPIA may be required.  Examples of when DPIA might be needed include:  
__\- We intend to implement a technology that automatically rejects a job application of an individual, whose profile does not fit the job requirements.  
__\- We plan to track location of our employees (e.g. drivers) and make decisions based on their delivery targets._

**Automated decision-making  
**Automated Decision-Making is a process when a decision is made which is based **_solely_** on automated processing (including profiling) and which produces significant legal effects or significantly affects an individual.  A recruitment aptitude test, which uses pre-programmed algorithms and criteria, where a decision is made by automated means based on that test is type of automated decision-making.  
In the EU automated decision-making is prohibited, unless:

  * An individual has given a clear and specific statement of consent
  * The processing is authorised by law
  * The processing is necessary for the performance or entering into a contract

_**How to comply?  
**At Anixter decision-making is not based **_solely_** by automated means.  However, if you intend to implement such process in the EU, please you must email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com)._

**Direct marketing in the EU  
**The EU has implemented various rules relating to direct marketing.  The rules that apply to us are mainly contained in the General Data Protection Regulations or GDPR and Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations or PECR.  
The GDPR applies whenever personal information is processed.  For example, it will apply to an email that identifies and individual e.g. [name.surname@anixter.com](mailto:name.surname@anixter.com), but not to [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).  
PECR applies to business to business and consumer marketing communications.  
Together the GDPR and PECR mean that typically consent for marketing communications is required, but we can contact corporate bodies.

**Sharing personal information  
**Generally, we are not allowed to share personal information with third parties unless certain safeguards, including contractual safeguards are in place.

_**How to comply?**  
- ** ** You may only share personal information we hold with another group company if they have a job-related need to know  
\- You may only share EU personal information with third parties, such as benefits providers, car leasing companies or credit reference agencies, under a written contract that complies with data protection legislation. If you are unsure, please contact the legal department._

## Changes to this privacy policy

This policy does not form part of any contract of employment or other contract to provide services. We may update this policy at any time. We will use reasonable efforts to notify you of any material changes, but reserve the right to update this policy without notice to you, so please check back regularly to obtain the latest copy of this policy.  
This policy does not override any applicable data privacy laws where we operate.

## Who to contact about this privacy policy

Any questions or issues regarding this policy should be sent to [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com). We will investigate any complaints about the use and disclosure of personal information that are not in accordance with this policy. 

With regard to personal information transferred from the EU or Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship, Anixter commits to resolve complaints about its collection or use of personal information transferred from the EEA or Switzerland in compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles.  EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact us at [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).  We commit to cooperating with EU data protection authorities and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved complaints concerning EU or Swiss personal information transferred from the EU and Switzerland, respectively.

**ANNEX A** ****

_EU-US AND SWISS-US PRIVACY SHIELD GUIDELINES_

**What is the purpose of these guidelines?  
**Anixter Inc. (in these guidelines “we” or “Anixter”) participates in the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks, which help us comply with data privacy laws that apply to personal information about employees located in the EU and Switzerland, which we receive in the US.  In these guidelines, we will refer to these frameworks as “Privacy Shield”.

**What is the scope of these guidelines?  
**Personal information means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified.  These guidelines apply to all managers, whose teams access or use personal information about employees located in the EU or Switzerland.  For simplicity, throughout this notice we will use the term “EU or Swiss personal information”, which includes personal information about EU or Swiss employees and contractors, as applicable.  
If you or your team accesses or uses EU or Swiss personal information, these guidelines apply to you and you must ensure that your direct reports follow these guidelines.

**What are the key requirements of these guidelines?  
**You must access EU or Swiss personal information on a strict need-to-know basis only.  Any access, use, disclosure, and storage of such information must comply with:

  * The Privacy Policy
  * These guidelines
  * The Employee Privacy Shield Notice
  * The Website Privacy Policy

Please note that any violation of these guidelines may be subject to appropriate disciplinary action.

**Who to contact about these guidelines?  
**Any questions or issues regarding Privacy Shield should be sent to Privacy Shield Contact at  [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).  Any government inquiries regarding Privacy Shield, including from the US Federal Trade Commission, any EU data protection authority, or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner must be referred to the Chief Compliance Office at [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles, Anixter commits to resolve complaints about its collection or use of EU or Swiss personal information.  Anixter further commits to cooperating with the EU data protection authorities and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland.

**What should I do, if I need to disclose EU or Swiss personal information to a third party**?  
You must not disclose EU or Swiss personal information to service providers or other providers without express consent of the Privacy Shield Contact.  If you require such consent, please email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).  The Privacy Shield Contact will work with the legal team to make sure appropriate contracts are in place with third parties who will receive EU or Swiss personal information.

**Opt-out mechanism for certain processing of EU or Swiss personal information?  
**Anixter should generally provide choice (opt-out) for onward transfers to other controllers, for direct marketing, and for processing of EU or Swiss personal information for purposes that are materially different from the original purposes of collecting EU or Swiss personal information.  For health/medical and other sensitive personal information, affirmative choice (opt-in) may be required.  Before engaging in any of the above activities, the Privacy Shield Contact should determine how to provide appropriate choice or otherwise address relevant Privacy Shield requirements.

**Access and other requests in relation to EU or Swiss personal information**?  
If an EU or Swiss employee requests an opportunity to access and/or correct his or her personal information or expresses any other concern regarding EU or Swiss personal information maintained by Anixter in the United States, you must follow the process set out at **Annex B**.

**Annual internal audit and verification  
**At least 3 months before the renewal of our self-certification to the US Department of Commerce under Privacy Shield, the Privacy Shield Contact will initiate a self-assessment to verify compliance with Privacy Shield and or making any changes of modification that are required to comply with the Privacy Shield.

You must comply with requests from the Privacy Shield Contact in relation to Privacy Shield and self-assessment. More specifically, you may be required to assist the Privacy Shield Contact with the following:

  * **Comprehensive review of compliance status with Privacy Shield.**   As part of the self-assessment, the Privacy Shield Contact will review the Privacy Shield policies and notices, verify that EU and Swiss employees are aware about and can exercise their rights under Privacy Shield, review and roll out Privacy Shield training and discipline procedures.
  * **Changes and modifications.**   If any changes or modification are necessary to comply with Privacy Shield, the Privacy Shield Contact will make such changes as appropriate.  The changes may relate to policies, mechanisms for obtaining consent and to processes in which _you_ are involved.

**Annual self-certification  
**At least 4 weeks before the certification due date with the US Department of Commerce, the Chief Compliance Officer or other authorized representative will sign the Privacy Shield Verification Form and will file a re-certification with the US Department of Commerce.  
The self-certification will be handled by the legal team, but you need to be aware that we will annually represent to US Department of Commerce our compliance with Privacy Shield.  It is therefore of paramount important that you follow these guidelines.

**Privacy Shield Contact  
**The Privacy Shield Contact is Chief Compliance Officer, who has delegated his authority with respect to Privacy Shield to members of legal and HR teams. Any questions or inquiries about Privacy Shield or these guidelines should be directed to [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).

**ANNEX B** ****

_RECOGNIZING A REQUEST IN RELATION TO PERSONAL INFORMATION_

**Why do I need to know this?  
**There are many privacy laws around the world. The rights that those laws give individuals over their personal information vary. Most commonly these include rights to access, erase, object and restrict processing personal information. Less commonly these include right to object to automated decision-making or request human interference or right to data portability.  
Anixter has put in place a centralized process to deal with requests from individuals seeking to exercise rights over their personal information. This process is required because these rights are not unconditional and certain requests can be rejected. We also need to ensure that we verify the identity of an individual requestor to prevent unauthorized access.

**What do I need to do?  
**You must:

  * be able to recognize a request to exercise rights over personal information; and
  * direct the request to [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com), relevant HR team or, in some cases, marketing team within 2 business days from receipt.

You **must not** attempt to reply to a request yourself.  You must be able to recognize a request to access personal information, because it may be illegal in your jurisdiction to limit individuals to a particular method of exercising their lawful rights. As a general rule if a request is from a customer, supplier or end user, please email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com). If a request is from an Anixter employee, please contact your HR team.

**Access**  
An individual may wish to see what personal information we process for him or her. 

**Rectification  
**Individuals generally have a right to have their inaccurate personal information corrected. Such request does not have to mention the phrase “request for rectification” and can be made to any part of our organization.

**Erasure**  
This is sometimes known as the “right to be forgotten”. If we do not need personal information for the purpose for which we have collected it or if processing is based on consent, then an individual will typically have right to request erasure of that personal information.  However, not all personal information can be deleted.  If we need personal information to comply with the law or have on overriding legitimate interest, we can reject a request to delete such personal information.

**Restriction**  
This right applies only in certain circumstances.  If such request is made and the right applies, then we would be permitted to store personal information, but not use it.  This right is closely related to the right to rectification (above) and right to object (below).  This right may apply in the following circumstances:

  * the individual questions the accuracy of their personal information and we verify this
  * personal information has been processed in breach of privacy legislation
  * we no longer need personal information, but the individual needs us to keep it (e.g. to defend a legal claim)
  * the individual has objected to our processing of personal information and we are considering whether our legitimate grounds override those of the individual

We expect that this type of requests will be less common, but you should, nevertheless, be aware that this may happen.

**Portability**  
This right allows individuals to obtain and reuse their personal information. This right applies in limited circumstances, if:

  * Processing is based on consent (for example, a tick box on a website) or contract with an individual; and;
  * Processing is carried out by automated means.

Outside Anixter an example could be a request to receive names of the songs you have listened to on a streaming service.  The idea is that the data will need to be provided in a commonly readable format such as CSV. There are various further limitations to this right, which is why we are not providing an example of when this right may apply to individuals interacting with Anixter.  If you suspect that an individual wishes to exercise their right to data portability, you need to email [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).

**Objection**  
This is, quite simply, a request to stop processing personal information. This may apply if personal information is processed on the basis of our legitimate interest and it will apply if personal information is used for direct marketing purposes.

This mainly will apply in a direct marketing context. If you receive a request from our customer wishing to no longer receive marketing communication, please forward it to our marketing team.

**Rights related to automated decision-making**  
Individuals may be entitled to state their objection to automated decision-making process, request human intervention or express his or her point of view about such process or contest the outcome of automated decision-making.  
Most decisions at Anixter are not made solely by automated means. If you believe that an individual wishes to exercise their rights related to automated decision-making, please contact [dataprivacy@anixter.com](mailto:dataprivacy@anixter.com).
